The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Zhuque Zi doesn't control the Cultivation Planet Crystal yet.
And Situ still needs time to possess his new body...
Once he awakens,
I will retrieve both my soul strand and Wan'er's.
Now that planet Suzaku is in chaos,
it's no longer suitable for cultivation.
But if I'm heading to planet Tian Yun,
I'll need to prepare thoroughly.
There is also the problem of Tuo Sen from the Land of the Ancient God...
This blood contains a trace of Ancient God blood
so it's perfect for my Ancient God body.
But this amount is far from enough...
The person I found under the Corpse Sect begging for help
must be the founding Ancestor of the Giant Demon Clan.
Perhaps I should take this chance to visit the Corpse Sect
and see if I can get more.
Brother Wang,
it’s been a while.
Do you still remember me ?
Brother Zhou,
long time no see.
It's wine from back then,
my last jar.
This wine is still the same as back then
and so are the people.
As the saying goes:
"Things remain the same, but it's the people that change."
"Spring at Wuling", poem by Li Qingzhao
But it seems that the people remain the same, and it's the things that have changed.
Since the Four Sect Alliance,
Brother Wang has gained a mighty reputation on planet Suzaku.
Let's toast to you.
Brother Zhou has a good master guarding him.
I'm sure that you also will
achieve great feats.
Brother Wang,
I have another toast for you.
Thank you for killing Li Yuanfeng,
sealing Xue Yue,
and avenging the Four Sect Alliance.
Brother Zhou,
since you were waiting for me,
please speak your mind.
It all began when
the Forsaken Immortal Clan activated the Reincarnation Tree.
East of the
Suzaku Continent
Mei Ji
Third Ancestor of the
Forsaken Immortal Clan
9-leaf Shaman
Old Thief,
don't think that destroying a Reincarnation Tree
will reverse the decline of your country of Suzaku !
Early stage Ascendant
yet you bark like a dog !
My clan
will win this war for sure !
Don't be so arrogant, Junior.
Yunque Zi
Second Ancestor of the
Forsaken Immortal Clan
Middle stage Ascendant
Senior Brother,
long time no see.
Thank you for saving me, Second Ancestor.
Greetings, Second Ancestor.
Should I call you Yunque Zi
or Second Ancestor of the Forsaken Immortal Clan ?
Titles are meaningless.
Senior Brother can call me however he likes.
You’re heavily injured.
If you fight me now
you will only accelerate your death.
Then why don't you kill me now !?
"Don't fight a desperate enemy,
always leave an escape route open."
Note: "The art of War", Sun Tzu
My Forsaken Immortal Clan
has a deal for you.
You know better than anyone
that the defeat of Suzaku is inevitable.
But my Forsaken Immortal Clan
is willing to split planet Suzaku in half with you.
We will rule separately
without interfering.
What do you think ?
Despicable...
We will meet in 3 months
at Mount Suzaku.
My Forsaken Immortal Clan will wait for your decision.
Find a cold, dark place
and recover quickly.
First Ancestor of the
Forsaken Immortal Clan
11-leaf Shaman
Do you remember
how many clansmen we sacrificed
to break the seal and send you into the country of Suzaku ?
You could’ve killed him,
why did you let him go !?
He has the Cultivation Planet Heart
and can control the Cultivation Planet Crystal.
Even if the Second Suzaku sealed the crystal,
he can still destroy it.
Even if his soul strand is inside it,
if you try to kill him
he will crush the crystal before his life ends
and billions of our people below 9-Leaf
will die with him.
I had secretly raised 4 candidates.
No matter the one he chose as successor,
we could've weakened Suzaku even more
and ensured our clan’s prosperity !
But Ancestor Xu and you were too impatient
and ruined the plan I painstakingly laid out.
It was all for nothing !
Why did you give him 3 months ?
What’s the point ?
3 months
is enough to subdue his last allies
and make him face reality !
To keep planet Suzaku,
he must surrender the Cultivation Planet Heart.
Remember,
we never wanted to kill the Suzaku.
We want our clan
to freely live on the surface of this planet again.
Why are you so sure
he will agree to your plan ?
In order to become the Suzaku,
he killed his own master.
Such a person
will never accept
that he has lost everything.
In the following months
Yunque Zi and the others besieged the Earth Soul Sect
and killed its Ascendant Ancestor.
They crippled the Heavenly Jade Sect Leader, Chu Yunfei,
and forced him to flee planet Suzaku.
The rank 5 country of Suiboku
has fallen
The rank 5 country of Mudan
has fallen.
The rank 5 country of Qin
Among planet Suzaku’s cultivators,
Zhuque Zi
is the only remaining Ascendant.
And very soon,
the Ancestral Spirits will bloom again.
When that happens,
Zhuque Zi
will have no chance left.
Everything unfolded as Senior Yunque Zi predicted.
So you were also chosen by Yunque Zi.
Of the four of us,
I only know three.
I possess Azure Dragon bloodline and the Emotionless domain.
Zi Xin was once Qian Feng’s cauldron
and has karma with him.
Senior Yunque Zi
wanted us to counter Zhuque Zi’s 2 disciples.
The third person
is you.
He said if you’re willing
you can meet him.
That way,
he can teach you the true use of the Staw Hat.
Tell Yunque Zi
that I won’t meet him.
Fine.
Will you give me
this jar of wine ?
I once fought Liu Mei
and recorded her domain
in this jade slip.
Whether you read it or not
is your choice.
Thank you.
Corpse Sect
Country of Zhao
Li Qingping
Corpse Sect Leader
Late stage Nascent Soul
This Divine Sense…
a Soul Transformation cultivator ?
Interesting.
Cao Yidou's Origin Soul
Planet Tian Yun's Mile Sect
Middle stage Soul Formation
A Soul Formation Origin Soul
is able to detect my presence.
Please spare me, Senior !
My sect's cultivation method
is highly sensitive to Divine Sense.
Which sect are you from ?
Junior...
Junior's name is Cao Yidou,
I'm a disciple of the Mile Sect on planet Tian Yun.
Planet Tian Yun ?
Why is someone from Tian Yun
on planet Suzaku ?
Senior,
my body was destroyed
so I bought a new one from the Corpse Sect.
But I didn't have enough spirit stones
for the prices on Tian Yun.
My only choice was to settle for
a cheaper option like planet Suzaku.
What do you know
about planet Tian Yun ?
Junior grew up there
and knows every detail !
If Senior plans to go,
I can guide you.
Very well.
Be my servant for 100 years
and in return
I’ll give you a Soul Transformation body.
This person seems strong.
It's better to gamble
than to provoke his wrath.
Cao Yidou
greets Master.
It's still here...
His bloodline is the purest
and he's at least Ascendant.
If I can take his blood,
it'll benefit me greatly.
Fog, disperse.
Little friend,
save me !
Save me !
Seal !
This Giant Demon body
can't be pierced by my celestial sword
but can be hurt by these vines.
I’ll use them to draw blood.
Little friend,
if you free me
and I’ll give you the main artifact of the Giant Demon Clan !
Lei Ji
Giant Demon Clan branch leader
This is…
a hint of Ancient God blood.
His blood is indeed useful to me.
Little friend,
if you accept to free me,
I’ll give you my clan’s strongest artifact:
the Heaven-Splitting Metal.
I will order the Giant Demon Clan of Suzaku
to obey you forever !
As long as you free me from this place,
I’ll even become your mount !
Little friend,
a Giant Demon’s body
is like a star compass.
It's able to traverse places
ordinary cultivators cannot.
The old monsters of the Cultivation Alliance
all want Giant Demons as mounts !
Once we pledge loyalty,
we never betray.
Free me
and I’ll serve you !
Since you took my blood,
you must need it.
My marrow holds
even more essence than my blood.
I will teach you how to extract it !
Something's wrong.
First, he baited me with promises.
Then, he stalled with explanations.
Losing his blood
should weaken him
and make his escape harder.
But he is ignoring it...
This isn't how someone that needs help would act.
Could it be...
Who are you ?
I'm Lei Ji, the leader of our branch of the Giant Demon Clan !
I once killed 3 9-Leaf Shamans
of the Forsaken Immortal Clan.
I was then chased by an 11-Leaf Warrior
and ended up captured by the Corpse Sect
and then sealed here.
If you free me,
every Giant Demon Clan member on Suzaku
will pledge themselves to you !
Little friend,
you…
I won't save you.
Saving you doesn't benefit me.
But if I leave you here,
I can come later to harvest more blood.
Which is much better.
Senior Lei Ji,
farewell.
He didn't want me to free him
but he was luring me into drawing more blood.
If I had continued,
it would've awakened his power
and help him escape.
If he had stayed half an incense stick of time
and continued to draw my blood,
it would have lured this vine inside my body
and allowed my soul to escape !
I REFUSE TO ACCEPT THIS !
I didn't expect that in this cold and gloomy Corpse Sect
I would find such a delicious smell.
A Soul Transformation that hasn't tasted a woman ?
A rare delicacy...
Little cultivator,
how about we…
experience the beauty of life ?
There is some debate among the fans about the real cultivation level of Yunque Zi. To be clear, the animation studio went with 10-Leaf Shaman in the character card but I don't think this is correct because:
n°1: Yunque Zi lived his early life infiltrated in the country of Suzaku and had to become a regular cultivator for that. Yunque Zi also doesn't display any tattoos.
n°2: Yunque Zi has a domain whereas the Forsaken Immortal Clan members don't have one with their method of cultivation (it's the same as Ancient Gods having a different cultivation system and thus not having domains).
n°3: Wang Lin explicitly says he is Middle stage Ascendant in the novel.
Counter-arguments:
n°1: Even if lore-wise Forsaken Immortal Clan members shouldn't have domains, there is a second example of one (which is Mei Ji, the Third Ancestor of the Forsaken Immortal clan that we see at the end of the episode with her charm domain).
n°2: There is a single dialogue where Yunque Zi mentions high level shamans and he includes himself in them.
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.